Guide to the Nicholas Scoppetta Papers 1974-2015 MS 3017
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Child Welfare, 1988-2014 (bulk, 1988-2008); 5.5 Linear feet
  - Subseries II.A. Child Welfare: General, 1988-2014
    - [Child Welfare: General] (3 folders), 2001 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1-3)
      Folder 3 holds contents from a binder, "Scan of Innovative Programs Supporting Children Without Guardianship, Presented to the Broad Foundation," 28 September 2001.
    - [Child Welfare: Wald Course] (4 folders), 2001 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4-7)
      Course material for "Child Abuse and Neglect, Law 585," taught by Professor Michael Wald at Stanford Law School, Spring 2001.
    - [Child Welfare: General], 2002-2003 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 8)
    - [Child Welfare: General], 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 9)
    - [Child Welfare: General], 2005 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 10)
    - [Child Welfare: General], 2006-2007 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 11)
    - [Child Welfare: General], 2007 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 12)
    - [Child Welfare: General], 2008-2010 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 13)
    - [Child Welfare: New Yorkers for Children], 2009-2014 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 14)
      Separated Materials Note
      Material relating to New Yorkers for Children, the nonprofit partner of ACS Scoppetta founded in 1996.
    - [Child Welfare: General] (3 folders), 2011-2013 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1-3)
      Includes material on the Evan B. Donaldson Adoption Institute Honoree-Benefit, May 2012 (Folder 2).
    - [Child Welfare: General, undated] (3 folders) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4-6)
    - Child Welfare & ACS (6 folders), 1996-2005 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7-12)
      From an accordion file Scoppetta labeled "Child Welfare & ACS."
    - Child Welfare: Reference (3 folders), 1988-2001 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 13-15)
      From an accordion file Scoppetta labeled "Reference Child Welfare."
    - Child Welfare: Important Reference (3 folders), 2001-2007 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1-3)
      From an accordion file Scoppetta labeled "Child Welfare / Important Reference."
    - Child Welfare: Child Fatality (5 folders), 1989-2000 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4-8)
      With a sheet (in Folder 4) itemizing the contents of Folders 4-8:
      I. ACS' Annual Reports (1989-1999) [NOTE: Only 1989-1995 present; Folders 6-8]
      II. Fatality Statistics (Internal Excel Spreadsheets for cases in calendar years 1998-2000) [Folder 4]
      III. Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles on Studies on Child Fatalities [Folders 4-5]
    - [Child Welfare: Marisol case] (2 folders), circa 1995-2011 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9-10)
      Material relating to the lawsuit known as Marisol v. Giuliani, named for the girl (born 1990) around whom it centered. Her physical and sexual abuse at the hands of her mother and mother's boyfriend led to the reformation of New York City's flawed Child Welfare System.
    - [Child Welfare: Elisa Izquierdo case], 1995-1997 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
      A memorandum and two copies of Scoppetta's statement, as Commissioner of the Administration for Children's Services (ACS), on the death of Elisa Izquierdo (1989-1995). Elisa was beaten to death by her mother in one of the most horrific instances of child abuse of the day. The case spurred Rudy Giuliani to replace New York's ineffective Child Welfare System with the ACS and to appoint Scoppetta its first commissioner.
    - [Child Welfare: Elisa Izquierdo case] RESTRICTED until 2070, 1996 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 12 RESTRICTED)
      Access Restrictions
      Contains a confidential draft report of the New York City Child Fatality Review Panel (3 January 1996) and two copies of a memorandum regarding the same (9 February 1996), which, because they name caseworkers and Elisa Izquierdo's siblings, are RESTRICTED until 2070.
  - Subseries II.B. Child Welfare: Printed Material, 1982-2012
    Printed matter on the subject of child welfare, mostly reports generated by the Association for Children's Services.
    The material is filed chronologically by date of publication.
    - New York State Supreme Court, Appellate Division, First Department, In the Matter of the Adoption of Male Infant Landaverde..., 1982 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 13)
    - Protecting the Children of New York: A Plan of Action for the Administration for Children's Services, 1996 December 19 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 14)
    - New York City Administration for Children's Services, Outcome & Performance Indicators, Status Report I, 1998 June (Offsite-box 6, Folder 15)
    - Protecting the Children of New York: A Plan of Action for the Administration for Children's Services, second printing (2 copies), 1998 October (Offsite-box 6, Folder 16-17)
    - The City of New York Administration for Children's Services, Accountability Review Panel Report 1996 and 1997, 1998 December (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - The City of New York Administration for Children's Services, Accountability Review Panel Report 1998 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - The City of New York Administration for Children's Services, Accountability Review Panel Report 1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, Division of Child Protection, Child Protective Services, Quality Improvement Management Plan and Outcomes, 1996-1999 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Administration for Children's Services, Division of Child Protection Child Protective Services Casework Practice Guide, first edition, 1999 June 7 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, Reform Plan Indicators Status Report 2, 2000 March (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, Realizing Reform: The Future of Children's Services in NYC [summary of conference proceedings], 2001 March 26-27 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, Five Years of Reform in Children's Services, 1996-2001 Reform Update, 2001 March (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, A Renewed Plan of Action for the Administration for Children's Services, 2001 July (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, Transition Briefing Document, 2001 October 15 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
      Has Scoppetta's annotations and loose, inserted notes.
    - NYC Administration for Children's Services, New York City's Child Welfare System: Status of Reform, New Yorkers for Children Annual Board Meeting, 2003 January 8 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Administration for Children's Services Strategic Plan Update, 2012 September (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
    - Administration for Children's Services (2 copies), n.d. (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subseries II.C. Child Welfare: Audiovisual, 1996-2002
    A large number of audiocassettes, VHS tapes, and two CDs/DVDs on the theme of child welfare. Most of the audiocassettes appear to be recordings of site visits Scoppetta made as Commissioner of the Administration for Children's Services. The VHS tapes are both professionally produced and recordings made by Scoppetta and/or ACS staff of television appearances, conference proceedings, etc.
    NOTE: The New-York Historical Society lacks audiovisual playback equipment.
    This material is arranged first by format—audiocassette, CD/DVD, or VHS—and then chronologically, except for the first five VHS tapes (episodes of the "Great Depression" documentary), which, for reasons of space, are housed in Box 9. All other VHS tapes are in box 10.
    - [Audiocassette] Brooklyn 6/4/96 #1, 1996 April 6 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Manhattan 6/6/96 #1, 1996 June 6 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Manhattan THM 6/6/96 #2, 1996 June 6 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Site visit 6/6/96 #1, 1996 June 6 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Site visit 6/6/96 #4, 1996 June 6 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Site visit 6/7/96 P.M. #5, 1996 June 7 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Site visit 6/7/96 #6, 1996 June 7 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] EAC 6/10/96, 1996 June 10 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Bronx THM 6/11/96 #1, 1996 June 11 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Queens 6/13/96 #1 THM, 1996 June 13 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Bed-Stuy 6/18/96 #1, 1996 June 18 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Bed-Stuy 6/18/96 #2, 1996 June 18 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] All Things Considered, 5/8/97, "Foster Care in the Hood," 1997 National Public Radio, 1997 May 8 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Joan Hollinger #1 6/26/98, 1998 June 26 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Joan Hollinger #3 6/26/98, 1998 June 26 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Non-profit boards & neighborhood-based services [labeled copy 2], 1999 December 20 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [Audiocassette] Non-Profit Board & Neighborhood-Based Service 12/20/00 [labeled "copy 1"], 2000 December 20 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [CD/DVD] ACS Speeches and miscellaneous, 2002 September (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [CD/DVD] Who's Watching the Children? [bootleg], n.d. (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [VHS] The Great Depression [episode 1]: A Job at Ford's, 1993 (Offsite-box 9)
    - [VHS] The Great Depression [episode 2]: The Road to Rock Bottom, 1993 (Offsite-box 9)
    - [VHS] The Great Depression [episode 3]: New Deal/New York, 1993 (Offsite-box 9)
    - [VHS] The Great Depression [episode 5]: Mean Things Happening, 1993 (Offsite-box 9)
    - [VHS] The Great Depression [episode 6]: To Be Somebody, 1993 (Offsite-box 9)
    - [VHS] The Great Depression [episode 7]: Arsenal of Democracy, 1993 (Offsite-box 9)
    - [VHS] Child Savers, reel #305, PBS [FRONTLINE], 1985 February 12 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Who Killed Adam Mann, Reel #1008, PBS [FRONTLINE], 1991 December 3 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] NIJ Research in Progress, Cathy Spatz Widom, Ph. D., The Cycle of Violence Revisited Six Years Later, 1995 April (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Good Day N.Y., Eric Brett Schn[eider?] w/ Jim Ryan, 1996 April 12 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Searching for Family: Moments in the Lives of Children in Foster Care [documentary by Kathryn Hunt] (KCTS Television, 1997) [2 copies] (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] NYC Council Committee on General Welfare (Crosswalks Television Network), 1997 December 9 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Take This Heart [for Press Preview Only], 1998 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] "Like it Is" [profile of ACS], 1998 February 8 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Wednesday's Child, 1998 September 9 & 16 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Council Committee on General Welfare (Crosswalks Television Network), 1998 September 10 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Silent Heroes: A Day in the Life of a Caseworker (ACS Video Unit), 1999 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] TASA [Teen Services Act Program] Graduation, 1999 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] ASFA [Adoption and Safe Families Act], Judge Sara Schecter, [1999] (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] ASFA [Adoption and Safe Families Act] Conference, Cooper Union, Carol Williams and Judge Schecter, 1999 January 14 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Committee on General Welfare & Women's Issues (Crosswalks Television Network) [2 tapes], 1999 January 21 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Child Welfare Conference Shane Salter Speech, 1999 July 22 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Committee on General Welfare / Women Issues (Crosswalks Television Network) [2 tapes], 1999 October 22 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Charlie [Rose?] / CNS on NBC, 1999 November 1 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Robyn Brown-Manning Family to Family Conference (ACS Video Unit), 1999 November 15 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] CNS on "Closeup," WB11 News, 1999 December 11 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Child Victims Model Courts Initiative, 2000 February (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Team Decisionmaking [sic] Involving the Family and Community in Child Welfare Decisions (Annie E. Casey Foundation), 2000 November (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] ACS Conference media Coverage, 2001 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Interview with Commissioner Nicholas Scoppetta (ACS Video Unit), 2001 February 2 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Family Separated, Channel 2 [CBS], 2001 April 26 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Children's Services Facility Walk-through inspection [2 tapes], 2001 August 22 (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Best Talk with A.C.S. Commissioner Nicholas Scoppetta, n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Beyond the System: A future for teens in foster care (Youth Advocacy Center) (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Caseworker and Attorney review a case and prepare for for [sic] a court appearance (ACS Video Unit) (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Caseworker Testimony in TPR Inquest (ACS Video Unit), n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Child Welfare Panel [labeled "copy 1"], n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] DLS Intake (ACS Video Unit), n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Expert Testimony in Fact Finding Hearing (ACS Video Unit) (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] IDCFS Pathways to Development, n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Interview with a DLS Attorney (ACS Video Unit), n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Judge Schechter & Judge Larabee (ACS Video Unit), n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Listen and Learn: a youth documentary (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] NYS Child Protection PSA (ACS Video Unit), n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Rikers Island Visiting Program (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Save Our Streets Show #312, n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Voices of Youth: Supporting Adolescents in Foster Care (Annie E. Casey Foundation) (Offsite-box 10)
    - [VHS] Welcome to ACS: The Administration for Children's Services (ACS Video Unit), n.d. (Offsite-box 10)
- Series III. FDNY, 2001-2015 (bulk, 2002-2009); 1.5 Linear feet
  This series covers Scoppetta's tenure as New York City's 31st Fire Commissioner, 2002-2009. Some earlier and later transitional items are present. Like the rest of the collection, these files appear to have been those Scoppetta kept at home, rather than his official, departmental files. As such, they are not comprehensive, and only hint at his daily working life.
  Series III is divided into two subseries, both arranged chronologically:
  Subseries III.A. FDNY: General, 2001-2015.
  Subseries III.B. FDNY: Audiovisual, 2002-2009.
  - Subseries III.A. FDNY: General, 2001-2015
    This subseries includes general material from Scoppetta's day-to-day activities as FDNY Commissioner. Note the files labeled "Vulcan Society" (Box 8, Folders 8-10), regarding the fraternal order of Black firefighters' discrimination lawsuit against the FDNY, which was settled in 2014.
    The material is arranged chronologically, with general FDNY material (Box 7, Folder 5, through Box 8, Folder 3), followed by the contents of several accordion files Scoppetta labeled "Labor/Management" (Box 8, Folders 4-7); "Vulcan Society" (Box 8, Folders 8-10); and "MANAGEMENT (REFERENCE)" (Box 8, Folders 11-18). Photographs of Scoppetta at various FDNY events are filed in Box 9, Folder 1.
    - [FDNY: General], 2001 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes a partially-filled spiral notebook labeled "FDNY 2001."
    - [FDNY: General] (2 folders), 2002 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6-7)
      Folder 3 includes the FDNY Memorial Day Ceremony Plan (24 September 2002) with Scoppetta's speech (delivered 12 October 2002).
    - [FDNY: General], 2003-2004 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
    - [FDNY: General], 2004 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
      Includes a copy of Terrorism and Counterterrorism: Understanding the New Security Environment. Readings & Interpretations by Russell D. Howard and Reid L. Sawyer (Guilford, Conn.: McGraw-Hill/Dushkin, 2004), inscribed to Scoppetta, with the latter's synopsis of the text.
    - [FDNY: General], 2005-2007 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
    - [FDNY: General] (3 folders), 2008-2009 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11-13)
      Includes printed FDNY Strategic Plan 2009-2010 (Folder 11) and accompanying material presented to the City Council on 29 October 2009 (Folder 13).
    - [FDNY: General], 2010 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
      Includes "Fire Department of New York Transition Document," with Scoppetta's notes "Draft Transition Doc. / The Missing Section 12-8-09."
    - [FDNY: General], 2010-2011 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
    - [FDNY: General], 2012-2015 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
    - [FDNY: General, undated] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
      Includes undated speeches, drafts, and notes (8 items).
    - [FDNY:] Job Action; RTs, 2005-2007 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
      From and accordion file Scoppetta labeled "Labor/Management."
    - [FDNY:] UFA Grievances (2 folders), 1996-2009 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5-6)
    - [FDNY: Firefighter exam booklets], 1999, 2002 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
    - [FDNY:] Vulcan Society (3 folders), 2008-2014 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8-10)
      The Vulcan Society is a fraternal organization of black New York City firefighters. A lawsuit brought by the Vulcan Society against the FDNY alleging discrimination in hiring practices and was settled in 2014.
    - [FDNY:] Management (reference) (8 folders), 1998-2007 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 11-18)
      The contents of an accordion folder marked "MANAGEMENT (REFERENCE)," which includes a mix of FDNY, ACS, and training material that appears themed toward improving management of FDNY through expertise gained at ACS. Much of this material was loose; only two segments were foldered: "Harvard School of Public Health & Kennedy School" (Folder 13) and "Public Sector / Media & Gov't" (Folder 15).
    - [FDNY:] "Exhibits" (2 folders), 2000-2004 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 19-20)
      Printed matter labeled (with sticky notes) "Ex 1," "Ex 2," etc., through "Ex 9" (except for "Ex 8," which is missing). Presumably exhibits used for some FDNY court case or presentation.
    - [FDNY:] Excerpt from Ginger Otis Book, circa 2014 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 21)
      Scoppetta's manuscript comments and corrections on excerpts from Ginger Adams Otis's book Firefight: The Century-Long Battle to Integrate New York's Bravest (New York: St. Martin's Press, 2015). The New-York Historical Society Library holds a copy of the book under call number F128 TH9505.N5 O85 2015.
    - [FDNY: newsclippings], 2002-2010 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 22)
      From a file Scoppetta labeled "Diversity" that may cover other FDNY issues.
    - [FDNY: photographs], 2002-2009 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
      Photographs of Scoppetta at various FDNY events, 2002-2009, with seven reproductions of historic Triangle Shirtwaist Fire images (25 March 1911).
  - Subseries III.B. FDNY: Audiovisual, 2002-2009
    A small number of CDs and DVDs from Scoppetta's tenure as 31st FDNY Commissioner. Includes press clips, speeches, and television news profiles.
    These items are arranged chronologically.
    - [CD] Digital Digest / FDNY clips, 2002-2009 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [CD] FDNY Speeches, 2004 June-2005 December (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [DVD] FDNY Women Firefighters Appearance on Today in New York - WNBC, 2006 March 10 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [DVD] News 12 Brooklyn Profile of Women FFs, 2006 April 4 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [CD] E53 / Scoppetta, 2006 December 11 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [CD] CNN Story on High-Rise Simulator, 2009 July 9 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [DVD] September 11, 2009 Headquarters Ceremony FDNY Civilian Response (3 copies), 2009 September 11 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [DVD?] NY1 / Cassidy, 2009 December 10 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
    - [DVD] New York Blood Center 50th Anniversary Videos, 2013 November 18 (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
      Scoppetta served on the board of the New York Blood Center, 2006-2015.
    - [CD] WTC Powerpoint, n.d. (Offsite-box 9 [in small archival box])
- Series IV. Memorabilia, 1970s-circa 2009 (bulk, 2002-2009); 1 Linear feet
  This series contains photographs of Scoppetta, awards he received, political pins, awareness ribbons, and lapel pins, many with post-9/11 sentiments.
  Series IV is divided into two subseries, both arranged chronologically:
  Subseries IV.A. Memorabilia: Photographs and awards, 1970s-2001 (the last four items in this subseries appear out of strict chronological sequence because their size and/or format.
  Subseries IV.B. Memorabilia: Political and lapel pins, commemorative medals, etc., 1978-2009.
  - Subseries IV.A. Memorabilia: Photographs and awards, 1970s-2001
    This subseries contains photographs of Scoppetta with significant figures like Mayor Abraham Beame and First Lady Barbara Bush, and awards he received throughout his long career, including one signed by Hillary Rodham Clinton (Box 9, Folder 3).
    This material is arranged chronologically, except for the last four items, which, because of their shape and/or size, are housed separately.
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta shaking hands with Abe Beame while former Mayor John V. Lindsay looks on., 1970s (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta posed with Abraham Beame and Deputy Mayor Judah Gribetz., 1970s (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Photograph] City Hall., 1970s (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
      Photographic reproduction of a painting of City Hall, inscribed "To Nick Scoppetta, With very best wishes and affection, Abe Beame."
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta speaking outside the Children's Aid Society's Pelham Fritz Apartments, 12-21 West 118th Street, Manhattan., circa 1987-1993 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta shaking hands with Barbara Bush., 1989 April 24 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
      With a letter from the First Lady thanking Scoppetta for her tour of the Children's Aid Society, 26 April 1989.
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta accepting an award from NYPD Commissioner William Bratton., 1996 January (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta with Rudy Giuliani., 1996 January 11 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
      Inscribed "Nick, A good friend, and exceptional public official, and a terrific guy. With great affection, Rudy."
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta with Rudy Giuliani., 1998 May 15 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
      Inscribed "Nick, You're doing a great job! Your friend, Rudy."
    - [Photograph] Michael Bloomberg, Nicholas Scoppetta, Rudy Giuliani, and Hillary Clinton seated at an event, possibly a 9/11 memorial. (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta playing chess with NYPD Commissioner Ray Kelly., n.d. (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Photograph] Scoppetta with New York Governor Mario Cuomo., n.d. (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
    - [Certificate] The Congressional Coalition on Adoption / Angels in Adoption Awards, 2001 / is hereby presented to Nicholas Scoppetta. (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
      Signed by Hillary Rodham Clinton, Sponsoring Member of Congress.
    - [Plaque] 1985 / Award / Presented to / Honorable Nicholas Scoppetta / From the Members / of the / Frank S. Hogan / Associates Inc. (Offsite-box 9)
      Scoppetta's badge as Assistant District Attorney for New York County is mounted on the plaque.
    - [Certificate] Children's Aid Society / Presented by the / Trustees / to / Nicholas Scoppetta / President / 1987-1993., 1993 October 20 (Oversize Large [NS12])
      With a reproduction of a historic photograph of children playing in a tenement-lined street.
    - [Poster] The Big Apple / You have to be a little crazy to live in New York, but you'd be nuts to live anywhere else. April '76., 1976 April (Oversize Large [NS12])